http://www.plan-international.org/privacy-and-cookies

Skip to main content
Privacy policy and cookie notice
Last updated: July 2019
Contact information
The Plan Limited Website, found at plan-international.org, including all information and materials contained on it, is managed by Plan Ltd, Dukes Court, Block A, Duke Street, Woking, Surrey GU21 5BH, UK ("Plan Ltd").
To contact us, please visit our contact page or call us on +44 (0) 1483 755155.
Our privacy policy
Plan Ltd is committed to ensuring the privacy of all our users. This Privacy Policy governs all pages on the domain plan-international.org. It does not apply to pages hosted by other organisations, including the websites of Plan International fundraising offices or third-party sites. The Plan Ltd Website (the “Website”) may be linked to the websites of such other parties, but those other sites may have their own privacy policies which apply to them.
By using the Website, you consent to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Plan Ltd may change the terms of this Privacy Policy from time to time and, if such changes are made, we will notify you of those changes by contacting you if appropriate or publishing the updated Privacy Notice on our website. Your continued use of the Website will be on the terms of this Privacy Policy as amended from time to time.
WHAT TYPES OF INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND STORE?
The type and amount of information we receive and store depends on how you use the Website. You can access most of the pages on the Website without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information. Our web servers collect anonymous logs during user visits to the Website. This information may be used to create aggregate statistics about how the Website is used (see our Cookies Notice below for more information about this).
We do not collect personal information (such as your name, e-mail address or country of residence) on the Website unless you choose to provide it. For example, where you express an interest in subscribing to our email updates.
By subscribing to our email updates, you have provided us with your consent to process your personal data and send you marketing information.
HOW DO WE USE INFORMATION COLLECTED?
Where you have provided your consent for your personal information to be processed by Plan Ltd and its service providers, it will be done in a secure environment and only used in connection with the purposes for which it is submitted. At Plan Ltd, we process personal data in order to send you email updates about the work we are doing, marketing information or as necessary for us to comply with our legal obligations.
SHARING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
The information you provide will not be sold. Where necessary, we will share your information with our service providers and where we have your permission, we will share your personal information with Plan International fundraising offices if they request details of subscribers to email updates in their territory. They may contact you inter alia to invite you to support their activities or to subscribe to their newsletters. Otherwise, we shall only share your personal information if we are required to disclose it by law.
If you choose to email us directly using the ‘Contact us’ facility, we have a legitimate interest to process your personal information for the purposes of reply or to forward to the appropriate Plan International office for action. E-mail addresses are not otherwise retained. E-mail addresses are not passed to any third party.
Sending data outside the European Union
In order to administer the site, we share personal data with third party service providers that perform functions on our behalf, such as a company that hosts our website.  They have access to personal data needed to perform their functions but may not use it for other purposes.  In some cases, this may involve processing personal data outside of the UK and European Union.
Furthermore, if you live in a country outside the European Union, the disclosure of your personal information as discussed above may involve the transfer of that information to Plan International fundraising offices outside of the UK and European Union.
Where your personal information is transferred to a service provider or another Plan International office based outside of the European Union, we will ensure that your data is protected to the same extent as in the European Union through one of the following safeguards:
Transfer to a non-EU country whose privacy legislation the ensures an adequate level of protection of personal data as determined by the European Commission; or
Put in place a contract with the service provider or fundraising office that means they must protect personal data to the same standards required by the European Union.
OPTING OUT OF RECEIVING MESSAGES FROM PLAN LTD
We will hold your personal information for as long as you continue to subscribe to our mailing list. Any e-mail we send you will enable you to opt out of receiving further e-mails from us. If you choose to unsubscribe from receiving further emails, we will immediately stop sending you any communications and we will remove your personal information from our system within six months. You can also request that we remove you from our mailing lists by contacting our Data Protection Officer (see details below).
YOUR RIGHTS UNDER THE DATA PROTECTION ACT and the general data protection regulation
The collection and use of personal information on this site is in accordance with the Data Protection Act 2018 and the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). More information can be found at the Information Commissioner's Office.
Complaints
If you wish to make a formal complaint to the supervisory authority where you live, or work or where you believe there has been an infringement of your rights under the GDPR, please contact the supervisory authority in the relevant EU Member state. In the UK the supervisory authority is the Information Commissioner’s Office.
ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION
You have rights of access to personal information that we hold about you, to correct or delete that information or, in some circumstances, to object to our processing of your information, under data privacy law. If you wish to exercise any of these rights or have any questions about this policy, please contact the Data Protection Officer.
Data Protection officer
For all queries relating to your personal information, please contact our Data Protection Officer at:
Data Protection Officer, Plan Limited, Dukes Court, Block A, Duke Street, Woking, Surrey GU21 5BH, UK or e-mail us at Data.Privacy@plan-international.org.
OUR COOKIE NOTICE
A cookie is a text-only piece of information that a website transfers to your web browser so that the website can remember who you are. A cookie will normally contain the name of the Internet domain from which the cookie has come, the "lifetime" of the cookie, and a value, usually a randomly generated unique number.
Plan Ltd uses cookies and analysis software for the purpose of enhancing your user experience. For example, measuring how many people are using each page of the website and for how long so that we can try to improve the quality of our website.
This information is not used to develop a personal profile of you.
By using our Website, you agree that we can place these types of cookies on your device.
Users have the opportunity to set their devices to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. To prevent the download of cookies, or otherwise control how cookies are used on your computer, please read the help information supplied with your Internet browser software, go to www.allaboutcookies.org, or read further instructions below.
OUR USE OF COOKIES
Google Analytics
The Website uses Google Analytics to help analyse how users use the site. This analytical tool uses 'cookies', which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information in an anonymous form.
The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Website (including your IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitors' use of the Website and to compile statistical reports on website activity for Plan International.
Plan Ltd will not (and will not allow any third party) to use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any personally identifiable information of visitors to our site. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any personally identifying information from any source as part of our use of the Google statistical analytics tool.
Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither Plan Ltd nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user.
By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. See Google’s Analytics overview for further information.
Google Ads
Plan Ltd uses first party Google Analytics cookies to collect anonymous information about visitors’ behaviour on the website. This information is used to create remarketing audiences based on specific behaviour, demographic, and interest data. These lists are shared with Google Ads.
These audiences can then be targeted by online advertising through Google Ads when visitors are browsing Google or its partner websites.
Plan Ltd will not (and will not allow any third party) to use Google Analytics or Google Ads to track or to collect any personally identifiable information of visitors to our website.
Find out how to opt out of personalised online advertising.
Crazy Egg
This Website uses a service called Crazy Egg to collect anonymous data about user behaviour on some of the Website’s pages, such as where they click or scroll to on a page. To do this, Crazy Egg will deposit a cookie in your browser.
Neither Plan Ltd nor Crazy Egg will use this information to personally identify our Website’s users. Please see Crazy Egg’s Privacy Policy. Find out how to opt out of Crazy Egg.
Facebook
This Website uses a Facebook cookie which creates a link between your visit to this Website and Facebook. This helps us to show users relevant content on Facebook and to learn how users are interacting with our content on Facebook. Facebook will collect data to enable this. Information on how Facebook handles its users’ data can be found here. See below for information on how to disable this cookie.
Twitter
This Website uses a Twitter cookie which creates a link between your visit to this Website and Twitter. This helps us to show users relevant promoted content on Twitter and to learn how users on Twitter are interacting with our advertising. Twitter will collect data to enable this. Information on how to opt out of Twitter’s interest-based advertising can be found here.
Third-party cookies
To enrich our content, we sometimes embed photos and video content from websites such as YouTube or Twitter. As a result, when you visit a page with content embedded from, for example, YouTube or Twitter, these sites may set a cookie.
This Website also has 'share' buttons to enable users of the site to easily share articles with their friends through social networks, for example, Facebook, Twitter or LinkedIn. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service.
Plan Ltd does not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third-party website for more information about these.
DISABLING AND ENABLING COOKIES
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings on your browser.
Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of this Website.
To disable cookies if you are using Microsoft Windows Explorer: Click on 'Tools' in the top menu, then on Internet Options, then on the tab marked 'Privacy'; Move the slider to the position corresponding to the level of cookie acceptance/denial acceptable to you.
To remove existing cookies if you are using Microsoft Windows Explorer: Click on 'Tools' in the top menu, then on Internet Options; In the section marked 'Browsing History', click on 'Delete...'; In the section marked 'Cookies' click on 'Delete cookies'; Click on 'Yes' or hit the 'Enter' key.
To disable cookies in other browsers see the links below:
Firefox cookie management
Chrome cookie management
Other browsers have similar cookie management abilities in their settings, please refer to your browser's 'Help' facility.
Find more detailed information on disabling cookies here: www.aboutcookies.org.
Tweet Share
Share
Email
